Guide to the Richard Finnie Collection ARS.0117
Archive of Recorded Sound
- 3. ethnic/field recordings and broadcasts
  - Middle East/North Africa
    - Tunisia Live Sound Effects, 1960-04; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Tunisia and Libya Live Sound Effects 4-5/60. Mule Cart Sounds; Crowd Noises at Tripoli Racetrack; Overloaded Radio [etc.], 1960; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Panama, Live Sound. Original, 1961-05; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - South Africa, Palabora. Railroad Work Sounds, Chanting, 1966; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Venezuelan Orchestra At Puerto Ordaz 10/1952; Dr. Jose Martucci, Piano, And Orchestra, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
- 4. jazz recordings and broadcasts
  - Herb Alpert, Louis Armstrong. Kraft Music Hall, TV, 1967-09-13; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Louis Armstrong, A Boy From New Orleans. TV Channel 7, 1972-09-09; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Burt Bales, Bob Helm, Dick Oxtot, Bob Mielke et al. Recorded by W.R. Heick for Dave Walker for Jazz Film, 1977-05; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - Burt Bales Live KGO. First Stereophonic Dixieland Jazz Broadcast. Pier 23 Nightclub. Bales, piano; Dick Oxtot, banjo ;Bob Mielke, trombone; Don Marchin, Bill Erickson, Frank Goudie. Estuary Jazz Band, 1959-05-10; 1 7" open reel tape folders (Audio 7)
  - Bechet - La Nuit (Ballet), 1963-12-15; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - The Big Band Sound and All That Jazz - Television Special, 1973-05-02; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
  - Dixieland, Monterey Jazz Festival, 1968-05; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - Phil Elwood KPFA broadcasts
    - Phil Elwood, Bechet Memorial, 1959-07-08; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 1)
    - Phil Elwood, Mouldy Jazz, Unedited, 1967-05-24; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Phil Elwood, Japanese Dixieland Jazz, 1962-02; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Phil Elwood, Jazz Archives. Kid Ory, Orson Welles, Standard School 1944-45, 1963-06; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Phil Elwood, Rowland Working Memorial, 1959-01-09; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - Phil Elwood, Muggsy Spanier Memorial [includes photograph and Christmas card from Ruth Spanier], 1967-02-15; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Phil Elwood, Fats Waller Program; The Feather Ball, An Introduction to Jazz by Cannonball Adderly, KPFA, 1966; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - Falter Jam Session Pt.2. Ralph Sutton (guest of honor), Al Hanson, John Falter, Joe Rushton, Skip Moore, Jack Coon, Bob Travis, Al Parker, Dave Wheat, Brad Collins., 1956-06-24; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - Falter Mixed Bag. Jazz and Jokes, 1970; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - Benny Goodman at Wolftrap. KQED TV, 1977-12-06; 1 7" open reel tape folders (Audio 6)
  - Coleman Hawkins Memorial. TV, 1969-07-08; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Earl Hines, Piano. Live KCBS, 1957; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - Earl Fatha Hines and Club Hangover All-Stars. Muggsy Spanier, Darnell Howard, Jimmy Archer, Popps Foster, Earl Watkins. 7-8/59, 1959; 5 7" open reel tapes (Audio 3, Audio 4, Audio 6)
  - The History of Jazz Piano. Earl Hines, Eubie Blake at UC Berkeley. KQED, 1977; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - Japanese Modern Jazz. Makoto O-oka, Suite for Jazz Band, 1960. From Japan Broadcasting Corporation tape. KPFA 7/3/61; Koto, 1961; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Jazz on Angel Island. Stone Age and Magnolia Bands, 1976-06-20; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - Just Jazz. Art Hodes, Wild Bill Davison, TV, 1971; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Ragtime with Max Morath. Eubie Blake. KQED TV, 1975-08-31; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Turk Murphy Jazz Band, Grace Cathedral. KMPX. Phil Elwood Commentary, 1977-10-21; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
  - Newport Jazz Festival 7/4/73. Tribute to Louis Armstrong. Channel 9 TV, 1973-11-05; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Dick Oxtot's Golden Age Jazz Band with Terry Garthwaite. Macy's San Francisco. KJAZ, 1978-09-12; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
  - Preservation Hall Jazz Band, Marin Junior College, 1975-07-11; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
- 5. miscellaneous
  - Jack Benny on TV, 1967-02-04; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Blooper's Soap. Courtesy W.A. Palmer, 1959-01-26; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Chaplin, Modern Times, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Noel Coward, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - Gibson Sextet. Song Rehearsal, 1959-12-14; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
  - History of Sound Recording, KSFR, 1962-06-01; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - John F. Kennedy on Cuban Missile Crisis, 1962-10-22; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - KPFA miscellaneous broadcasts
    - Cohen on the Telephone, produced and narrated by Byron Bryant, KPFA, 1968-09; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    - Cohen Gets Married. KSFA, 1959-05; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Croswell Speech Reel 1, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Anna-Livia Plurabelle; Brendan Behan on James Joyce. KPFA, 1963-03-17; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Sing Me A Song of Social Significance, KPFA, 1962-02-23; 1 3" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Dr. George McManus, piano, 1964-02-23; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
  - Minesolini [?]; Xmas Music. Both Tracks To Be Re-recorded, Background Hum, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Miscellaneous, Off-The-Air, Mostly Popular, 1956-12-15; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - Edith Piaf. I Regret Nothing, KQED TV, 1976-03-06; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Popular Discs of the Late 20's, Early 30's [voice of Finnie at end], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - Redwood Empire Score. Carmen Dragon, 1965; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Rock at the San Francisco Yacht Club, Belvedere. Cleveland Wrecking Company, Marble Farm, 1968-09-14; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)